Guide to the Walter L. Pforzheimer Collection of Frank Richard Stockton
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- November 2000 Acquisition, 1829-1965; 11.88; (22 boxes) + 17 broadside folders, 2 object storage items, 1 framed art item
  - Papers Relating to Frank Richard Stockton
    - Letter: William Smith Stockton to Emily H. Drean Stockton, 1829 (Box 10)
    - Robert Underwood Johnson, death, 1937 (Box 10)
    - "The Queen's Museum," contract and letters, 1906 (Box 10)
    - Letter: Irving Bacheller, undated (Box 10)
    - Letter: Amelia Barr to R.W. Gilder, 1889 (Box 10)
    - Letters: A. Castaigne to Henry Rood, 1906-1909 (Box 10)
    - The Century Association, exhibit, 1937 (Box 10)
    - Letter: Robert W. Chambers to Margaret Deland, undated (Box 10)
    - Letter: George William Curtis, 1879 (Box 10)
    - Letter: Elizabeth B. Custer, undated (Box 10)
    - Letter: Charles A. Dana, 1888-1890 (Box 10)
    - "The Author of 'The Lady or the Tiger?'" letters to Buel Carey, 1886-1891 (Box 10)
    - Memorandum book, 1848-1952 (Box 10)
    - "A Story of Champaigne," Southern Literary Messenger, 1861 (Box 10)
    - Letters regarding "The Magic Egg", 1894 (Box 10)
    - "The Merry Chanter," contract, 1889 (Box 10)
    - "Mrs. Cliff's Yacht," contract, 1896 (Box 10)
    - "The Osmer Aerolite," contract, 1903 (Box 10)
    - Robert Bridges, "Overhead in Arcady," photostats of my illustrated, signed copy, undated (Box 10)
    - "Personally Conducted," contract, 1889 (Box 10)
    - "Pomona's Travels," contracts, 1894 (Box 10)
    - Ms. Edith M. Thomas on the death of Thomas B. Aldrich, undated (Box 10)
    - Letters: Edith M. Thomas, undated (Box 10)
    - "Francis Thompson," by Shane Leslie, the Adelman Collection, 1935 (Box 10)
    - Letter: Henry Van Dyke, undated (Box 10)
    - Letter: Charles Dudley Warner, 1874 (Box 10)
    - Kate Douglas Wiggin, Broadside of Public Reading, 1908 (Box 10)
    - Letter: Mary E. Wilkins (Freeman), 1888 (Box 10)
    - Letters: Mary E. Wilkins Freeman to Henry Rood, 1906 (Box 10)
    - Libraries, 1936-1937 (Box 10)
    - Reviewing copies, 1936 (Box 10)
    - The Trade, 1936 (Box 10)
    - Letters to Rossiter Johnson, 1876-1916 (Box 10)
    - "Rudder Grangers Abroad," contract, 1891 (Box 10)
    - "Rudder Grange," contract, 1879 (Box 10)
    - Letters regarding "Rudder Grange", 1886 (Box 10)
    - Letter regarding "The Romance of a Mule-Car", 1896-1897 (Box 10)
    - Letter to Harper's, 1880 (Box 10)
    - Last will, 1893 (Box 10)
    - Letters to The Century Co (Editors), 1882-1897 (Box 10)
    - Autograph book extracts (from Richmond), undated (Box 10)
    - WLP and FRS family correspondence, 1935-1938 (Box 10)
    - Unidentified letters, FRS, [circa 1864-1898]; 5 (Box 10)
    - Brewer, Reginald, 1935 (Box 10)
    - John Carter Library Brown, 1934 (Box 10)
    - Cantrell, Mrs. George E., 1936 (Box 10)
    - McAllister correspondence, 1934 (Box 10)
    - Morton, Mrs. David C., 1936 (Box 10)
    - Rosenfeld, Paul, 1936 (Box 10)
    - Yale University Library, 1934-1935 (Box 10)
    - "The Dusantes," contract, 1888 (Box 10)
    - "Fanciful Tales," contracts, 1887-1894 (Box 10)
    - Letters regarding "The Squirrel Inn", 1889-1890 (Box 10)
    - Letters regarding "The Floating Prince", 1880-1881 (Box 10)
    - "The Squirrel Inn," contract, 1891 (Box 10)
    - "The Floating Prince," contract, 1881 (Box 10)
    - Wallack's Theatre, "The Lady and the Tiger", 1888 (Box 10)
    - Stockton, Frank R., correspondence, 1873-1899 (Box 11)
    - Stockton, Marion E., correspondence, 1892 (Box 11)
    - Letters, [circa 1963-1964]; 3 (Box 11)
    - Signed letter, portrait of FRS, 1898 (Box 11)
    - Assorted signed Stockton letters, undated; 2 (Box 11)
    - Illustrations by Bensell, undated (Box 11)
    - Unidentified letters signed, transcripts, 1870-1888; 2 (Box 12)
    - Mrs. F. R. Stockton photograph, undated (Box 12)
    - Unidentified, 1872-1876 (Box 12)
    - John R. Stockton poem, undated (Box 12)
    - Letters: Mary A. Hallock to FRS, undated (Box 12)
    - Letters: William Preston Johnston, 1896 (Box 12)
    - Letter: William Dean Howells, 1897 (Box 12)
    - Letter: May Robson, "Rudder Grange", undated (Box 12)
    - Letter: Thomas A. Janvier, "The Great War Syndicate", undated (Box 12)
    - Letters: Hamlin Garland, undated (Box 12)
    - Yone Neguchi, a pamphlet, undated (Box 12)
    - Letters: Simon Newcomb, 1888 (Box 12)
    - Letter: Elizabeth B. Custer, 1896 (Box 12)
    - Letter: Whitelaw Reid to Charles Collins, 1879 (Box 12)
    - Joel Chandler Harris, letter, signed, undated (Box 12)
    - Letter: William Allen Bryant to Mary Mapes Dodge, 1876 (Box 12)
    - Letter regarding "Stephen Skarridge's Christmas", 1876 (Box 12)
    - Brooke Mansfield, FRS autograph manuscript, undated (Box 12)
    - Amelie Rivers to FRS, 1888 (Box 12)
    - Letter: Edward Everett Hale, 1884 (Box 12)
    - Letter: Richard Watson Gilder, 1895 (Box 12)
    - Letter: JLA Ward to Charles Collins, 1890 (Box 12)
    - Letter: William Winter to St. Nicholas, 1874 (Box 12)
    - Letter: "The Lady or the Tiger?" (opera) Grace Greenwood to FRS, 1887 (Box 12)
    - Joseph Jefferson greeting card, undated (Box 12)
    - Letters: Robert J. Burdette, 1889 (Box 12)
    - Letters: Mary Virginia Ferhune to Mary Mapes Dodge, undated (Box 12)
    - Letters: Morse from Stoddard, Garrison and Wilkins, 1879 (Box 12)
    - Letters: Brander Matthews, 1888 (Box 12)
    - Letter: Charles Henry Webb, 1895 (Box 12)
    - Letter: Edna Dean Proctor, undated (Box 12)
    - Letter: William Henry Crane, 1894 (Box 12)
    - Helen Hunt: "The Singer's Friend", undated (Box 12)
    - Letter: Benson J. Lossing, 1875 (Box 12)
    - Robert Bridges, Christmas card and poems, undated (Box 12)
    - Letters: "The Forensic and Literary Circle", 1850 (Box 12)
    - Letter: Henry Cuyler Bunner, undated (Box 12)
    - Letter: Julia Marlowe to Minnie Dwight, undated (Box 12)
    - Letter regarding St Nicholas Magazine, 1873 (Box 12)
    - Letters: George W. Cable, 1875 (Box 12)
    - Letter: Richard Harding Davis, undated (Box 12)
    - Letters: A. B. Frost, undated (Box 12)
    - Letters: Kate Douglas Wiggin (Riggs), undated (Box 12)
    - Letters: Hjalmar H Boyeson, 1875 (Box 12)
    - Letter: Bronson Howard, 1896 (Box 12)
    - Letter: Thomas Bailey Aldrich, 1885 (Box 12)
    - Letter: Margot, Lady Asquith, 1892 (Box 12)
    - Letter: Edith M. Thomas, 1893 (Box 12)
    - Letter: Oliver Herford to Minnie Dwight, undated (Box 12)
    - Letter regarding "Ting a Ling", undated (Box 12)
    - Letter: Francis Davis Millet, undated (Box 12)
    - Letter regarding "The Adventures of Captain Horn", 1895 (Box 12)
    - Letter: John Burroughs to Minnie Dwight, 1898 (Box 12)
    - Letter: Laurence Hutton, undated (Box 12)
    - Letters regarding "The Squirrel Inn", 1900 (Box 12)
    - Celia Thaxter, "For Thoughts", undated (Box 12)
    - Poem: Grinwell Willis, undated (Box 12)
    - Letter: Robert Underwood Johnson, 1889 (Box 12)
    - Letter to Charles Collins, 1874 (Box 12)
    - Letter regarding "The Squirrel Inn", undated (Box 12)
    - Letter: Celia Thaxter to Editors of Scribner's, undated (Box 12)
    - Letter regarding "The Spectral Mortgage", 1898 (Box 12)
    - Letters: "The Morning Journal", 1895 (Box 12)
    - Letters: James Whitcomb Riley, 1891 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence with Mark Twain (Samuel Clemens), 1885-1902; 2 (Box 12)
    - Photograph, FRS in carriage
    - 2 Notebooks of letter transcripts, undated; 2 (Box 12)
    - Unidentified letters and articles, undated (Box 12)
    - The Century Magazine, 1884 (Box 12)
    - St. Nicholas Magazine, 1887 (Box 12)
    - Stockton photographs
    - Cash book, 1888-1902 (Box 13)
    - A Fortunate Opening: manuscript, undated (Box 13)
    - The Bibliography printed in the Captain's Tall Gate, compiled by Marion E. Stockton, with related correspondence and clipping, 1941, undated (Box 13)
    - Pomona's Travels: typescript, undated (Box 13)
    - Manuscript book: manuscript, undated (Box 13)
    - The Gudra's Daughter: manuscript, undated (Box 13)
    - The Griffon and the Minor Canon: manuscript, undated (Box 13)
    - Our Tavern: manuscript, undated (Box 13)
    - Pocket notebook, 1880-1881 (Box 13)
    - The Squirrel Inn: manuscript, undated (Box 13)
    - Scrapbook, undated (Box 14)
    - A Jolly Fellowship: manuscript, undated (Box 14)
    - Journal, 1882-1885 (Box 14)
    - House of Martha: manuscript, undated (Box 14)
    - The Christmas Shadrach: manuscript, and printer's copy, undated (Box 14)
    - Personally Conducted: manuscript, 2 volumes, undated; 2 (Box 15)
    - The Stowaway. Portion of original manuscript (Box 15)
    - The Christmas Before Last: manuscript, undated (Box 15)
    - Pomona's Bridal Trip: manuscript, undated (Box 15)
    - A Borrowed Month. 2 volumes: manuscript, undated; 2 (Box 15)
    - The Dusantes: manuscript, undated (Box 15)
    - Manuscript book: manuscript, undated (Box 15)
    - Notes, index cards, printed material, undated; 7 (Box 16)
    - A bibliographical list of the works of Mr. Stockton: typescript, undated (Box 16)
    - Stockton, Frank R.: ALS to Mr. Seiber, 1895 Jan 9 (Box 17 (Oversize))
    - Photographs and photostats of letters, 1894, undated (Box 17 (Oversize))
    - Portfolio of drawings of "Rudder Grange" by A. B. Frost, undated (Box 17 (Oversize))
    - Photograph, FRS in carriage, undated (Box 18 (Oversize))
    - "To Thomas Mann," Dorothy Thompson, 1937 (Box 18 (Oversize))
    - Photostat articles, undated (Box 18 (Oversize))
    - Framed engraving of Stockton, undated (Box 18 (Oversize))
    - "Pomona's Travels," drawings by AB Frost, undated (Box 19 (Oversize))
    - "The Pirate Poodle by Caroline Wells," pencil drawing, undated (Box 19 (Oversize))
    - Prints and drawings, undated; 11 (Box 19 (Oversize))
    - Posters for books by FRS, with related material, undated (Box 20 (Oversize))
      Includes posters for: "The Adventures of Captain Horn," "The Squirrel Inn," and "Mrs. Cliff's Yacht"
    - Photograph of Walter L. Pforzheimer as a child, undated (Box 20 (Oversize))
    - A cartoon print: "Some Seasonable Novelties Suitable for a Discerning Public", undated (Box 20 (Oversize))
    - Prints: "A Tragic Tale of Tea by Carolyn Wells" and "A Serious Question by Carolyn Wells", undated (Box 20 (Oversize))
    - "At the Photographer's," drawing, undated (Box 20 (Oversize))
    - 3 Yale University lithographs, undated (Box 20 (Oversize))
    - Art Treasures of America, India proofs, undated (Box 20 (Oversize))
    - "Little Kime and her Pets:" illustration, undated (Box 20 (Oversize))
    - "Bloodhounds in America by John D. Howe and Charles E. Duffie," sketch, undated (Box 20 (Oversize))
    - Maude Adams Calendar, undated (Box 20 (Oversize))
    - "The Tale of the Pygmy Fleet," drawing, undated (Box 20 (Oversize))
    - "The German Band by Malcolm Douglas," sketch, undated (Box 20 (Oversize))
    - "Santa Claus Puzzled," sketch, undated (Box 21 (Oversize))
    - Drawings, undated; 9 (Box 21 (Oversize))
    - Original A. B. Frost drawing, signed, undated (Box 21 (Oversize))
    - Unidentified articles, 1886-1901 (Box 21 (Oversize))
    - "The Story of Robin Hood," sketch, undated (Box 21 (Oversize))
    - "Barbara Cries," sketch, undated (Box 21 (Oversize))
    - 1 unidentified illustration, printed, undated (Box 21 (Oversize))
    - "Race for a Whale," drawing, undated (Box 21 (Oversize))
    - "Paris Exhibition Gate," drawing, undated (Box 22 (Broadside))
    - "The Peina Mercedes," drawing, undated (Box 23 (Broadside))
    - "Fashionable Paris," drawing, 1899 (Box 24 (Broadside))
    - "The Oregon in Punta Arinas Harbor," drawing, undated (Box 25 (Broadside))
    - "Merrimac under Fire," drawing, undated (Box 26 Broadside))
    - "Farragut and the Signal Boy," drawing, undated (Box 27 (Broadside))
    - "Surrender of the Colony," drawing, undated (Box 28 (Broadside))
    - "Colony Club," drawing, undated (Box 29 (Broadside))
    - "The Queens Museum and Other Stories" by FRS, 7 original drawings, 1906 (Box 30 (Broadside))
    - "The Queens Museum and Other Stories" by FRS, 7 original drawings, 1906 (Box 31 (Broadside))
    - "The Queens Museum and Other Stories" by FRS, 7 original drawings, 1906 (Box 32 (Broadside))
    - "The Queens Museum and Other Stories" by FRS, 7 original drawings, 1906 (Box 33 (Broadside))
    - Vernon Howe Bailey sketch for Century, undated (Box 34 (Broadside))
    - "Residence of Lucy Maxwell," painting, undated (Box 35 (Broadside))
    - "Comfortable Quarters," painting, undated (Box 36 (Broadside))
    - Framed poster: "The Queen's Museum and Other Fanciful Tales" Frank R. Stockton with illustrations by Frederick Richardson, undated (Box 37 (Broadside))
    - Framed photograph of Stockton, undated (Box 38 (Broadside))
  - Restricted Fragile
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted fragile material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
    - Album of sea weed specimens, undated (Box 39 (Art))
    - Handkerchief, silk, undated (Box 40 (Art))
    - Bookmark, silk, undated (Box 40 (Art))
    - Printing block, wood, 1886 (Box 40 (Art))
      With advertisement for FRS, wood engraver, Philadelphia
    - Jar, ceramic, signed by FRS, undated (Box 40 (Art))
    - Walking stick, undated (Box 41 (Art))
    - Keith, Dora Wheeler. Oil painting: portrait of FRS, undated (Box 42 (Art))
- November 2000 Acquisition Addition, 1863-1993; 0.5; (2 boxes)
  Materials in this grouping were removed from the Walter L. Pforzheimer Papers in 2007. Personal names and titles of works have not been standardized. Contents are similar to those in the first grouping.
  - Papers Relating to Frank Richard Stockton
    - Birch, Robin Hood Print (Box 43)
    - Cable, George W., Home Culture Clubs, 1888 May (Box 43)
    - Frost, A. B., letters and writings, 1890 Feb 19 (Box 43)
    - Frost, A. B., "Time skips through the air" (Box 43)
    - Kemble, "The distant Negros let fall their hoe hands", 1896 (Box 43)
    - Leland, Charles Godfrey, Brass work for boys and girls (Box 43)
    - Leland, Charles Godfrey, Merman, 1892 Jul 12 (Box 43)
    - Leland, Charles Godfrey, Patty O'Scram, 1887 (Box 43)
    - Leland, Charles Godfrey, Story of Samuel Jackson (Box 43)
    - Leland, Charles Godfrey, letters, 1863, [1889?] (Box 43)
    - Mitchell, Donald G., letters, 1886 (Box 43)
    - Redwood, A.C. Infantry in 1862 (Box 43)
    - Remington, Frederic, "Endion", 1891 Apr 21 (Box 43)
    - Stockton, Frank R. to Mr. Clark, 1877-1880 (Box 43)
    - Stockton, Frank R., essay (Box 43)
    - Twain, Mark, suppressed plate from Huckleberry Finn (Box 43)
    - Williams Reese Company, correspondence and booklet, 1993 (Box 43)
    - Unidentified photostats (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Keller, A. J., Kate Bonnet proofs, 1902 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Exhibition Sign: Frank R Stockton, centenary exhibit (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Frost, A. B., 1902 Jan (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - One a Week: printed, 1890, 1900 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Frost, A. B., illustrations (Box 44 (Oversize))
- January 1997 Acquisition Addition, 0.33; (2 boxes) + 2 broadside folders
  - Papers Relating to Frank Richard Stockton, [circa 1898-1890]
    - The Casting Away of Mrs. Lecks and Mrs. Aleshine (New York: The Century Co., 1898). Illustrations by Frederic Dorr Steele, in ink, pencil, and charcoal, [circa 1898] (Box 45 (Oversize))
      Mounted in an album, inscribed by Steele to Pforzheimer
    - The Casting Away of Mrs. Lecks and Mrs. Aleshine. Posters (The Century Co.), undated (Box 46 (Oversize))
    - "Exhibition in honor of the centenary of Frank R. Stockton (April 5, 1834-April 20 1902), sponsored by the Yale Undergraduate Associates, from the collection of Walter L. Pforzheimer, Yale 1935." Poster, undated (Box 46 (Oversize))
    - "Lecture on Frank Stockton by Professor [William Lyon] Phelps." Poster, undated (Box 46 (Oversize))
    - The Merry Chanter. Illustrations by Charles Dana Gibson, in ink, [circa 1889-1890] (Box 46 (Oversize))
      3 illustrations:
      Single figure of sailor from rear. Headpiece to Chapter XIV (page 130)
      "Captain Bodship." Profile of old sailor with pipe, facing right. Headpiece to Chapter X (page 88)
      Three figures, man to left wearing artist's smock. Appeared in The Century Magazine, 1890 February (volume 39, number 4, page 553) with title, "I don't know that it's my place to give advice."
    - The Merry Chanter. Illustrations by Charles Dana Gibson, in ink, undated (Box 47 (Broadside))
      1 illustration:
      "Please, Sir, will you tell us your story?" Seven figures gathered in a semi-circle, looking at bearded man in a vest (page 47)
    - The Merry Chanter. Illustrations by Charles Dana Gibson, in ink, undated (Box 48 (Broadside))
      2 illustrations:
      "'Look at him!' cried Doris." Woman and man in ship's prow (page 35)
      "The Pie Ghost." Several figures regarding pie mysteriously poised on a sill (page 123)